https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
It's Easter.
Jsou velikonoce.
So what?
No a?
After Easter everything should smell nice.
Po velikonocích má všechno vonět.
And you had to steal my stuff?
A to jsi musela krást věci?
In my sleep?
Ve spánku?
If you were awake, you wouldn't have given them to me.
Kdybys byl vzhůru, tak jsi mi je nedal.
You bet!
To si piš!
Ozzak!
Ozzáku!
To the shop!
Do krámu!
Chop, chop, chop, chop, chop!
Šup, šup, šup, šup, šup!
It's Easter already?
To už jsou velikonoce?
That's not much of an Easter lunch.
To není moc velikonoční oběd.
So you're not even fasting first?
Takže to ti nejdřív půst?
Come on, don't be grumpy.
No, no, tak nebuď podrážděná.
I'm just saying, it's Holy Saturday.
Já jen, že je Bílá sobota.
And we usually have schnitzel.
A to bývají řízky.
The curtains are usually hung up by now too.
Taky už bývají pověšeny záclony.
I'm ironing.
Tetím.
Bro, you've really seen through it all.
No brácha, fakt jsi prokouk.
I smell like some flower.
Smrdím jako nějaká kytka.
That's aloe vera.
To je aloe vera.
Great, so I smell like some woman.
Dobře, tak smrdím jako nějaká ženská.
I can't go to the cesspit tonight smelling like this.
Takhle večer k žumpě nemůžu.
So I bust my back doing laundry and then he goes to the cesspit in it, right?
Tak já se s tím peru a on v tom potom jde k žumpě, jo?
Relax, it'll definitely be some pub, right bro?
Klid, to bude určitě nějaká hospoda, viď brácha?
Sure.
No jasně.
Yeah.
No.
That's a relief.
To se mi ulevilo.
We're going with Metlos to check out the spring ferret fair.
Jdeme se tam s Metlošem podívat na jarní burzu tchořů.
Great.
No bezva.
And then we're going to help Ziza wash the crap wagon.
A potom jdeme Žížovi pomoct umýt hovnotu.
Why don't I just skip it?
Proč já si na to nevykašlu?
It's Easter, come on.
Tak jsou velikonoce.
Bro, can I go caroling by myself this year?
No brácha, že můžu letos chodit na koledu sám.
Out of the question.
Nepřipadá v úvahu.
People laugh at me that I'm always dragging my younger brother around.
Jakože se mi směje, že se o pořád tahá mladšího bráchu.
You're not dragging your brother, your brother drags you.
Netaháš bráchu, brácha tahá tebe.
Usually literally.
Obvykle doslova.
Last time the building manager had to drag you both back.
Před lůní vás oba dotáhla správcová.
Yeah, but that was a bad year.
No, jenže to byl blbej rok.
Just one?
Jeden?
She's been putting pamphlets from the alcohol treatment society in my mailbox for two years now.
Už dva roky mi hází do schránky letáčky společnosti pro léčbu alkoholismu.
As in, for you?
To jako pro tebe?
You're an alcoholic?
Ty máš alkoholismus?
Hey.
Čau.
What are you doing?
Co to děláš?
I'm doing blue ones this year.
Letos budu dělat modrou.
I'll give you some of mine.
Tak já ti dám nějaký ode mě.
We don't need any charity.
My žádný milodary nepotřebujeme.
What'll you have?
Co si dáš?
Coffee.
Kafe.
You drink coffee?
Ty piješ kafe?
Yesterday at one in the morning I was washing windows and now I have to hold on till my curtains get washed a second time.
Včera ve jednom jsem myla okna a teď musím vydržet, než se mi podruhý doperou záclony.
You wash them twice too?
Ty je taky pereš dvakrát?
No.
Ne.
Dad wrung them out and they fell on the street.
Vyždímal je otec a vypadly mu na ulici.
See ya!
Čus!
I'll have a quick one.
Dám si jednu rychlovku.
What's the rush?
Co ten spěch?
I'm going to braid my love.
Jdu plést svou lásku.
I've got willow branches you've never seen the likes of.
Mám proutí, to jste v životě neviděli.
Yeah, where'd you get them?
Jo, kde jsi se hnal?
Why?
Proč?
You don't want to tell your brother, do you?
Nechceš to říct bráchovi, že ne?
No, but Sasa learned to braid amazing stuff from willow.
Ne, ale Saša se naučila plést zproutí báječný věci.
I'm just starting, but I can do an Easter whip already.
Teprve začínám, ale pomlázku už umím.
Sasa, a man has to braid his own Easter whip.
Sašo, pomlázku si chlap musí uplést sám.
But how dare he tell me that?
Ale jak se mi to dovolil?
He said a man.
Říkal chlap.
We're in the lead.
Vedeme.
Wait, so where can Sasa go for the willow?
Počkej, tak kam se může Saša pro to proutí?
Simona, it's dangerous there.
Simono, je to tam nebezpečný.
Dangerous?
Nebezpečný?
Really.
Fakt.
That guy's got carnivorous plants there.
Líďák to tam má masožravý kytky.
Cheapskate.
Krkoune.
I'm not kidding.
Nekecám.
Bye.
Čus.
Oh God.
Panebože.
I'm gonna spend the whole weekend listening to who's got the bigger Easter whip.
To zas budu celý víkend poslouchat, kdo má větší pomlázku.
Stupid Easter.
Blbý velikonoce.
It's not stupid.
Nejsou blbý.
I just can't wait for Monday.
Už aby bylo aspoň pondělí.
You know, the carolers will come.
Víš, přijdou koledníci.
I don't care about carolers.
Na koledníky kašlu.
The main thing is Dad and my sisters are finally leaving and I can get some sleep.
Hlavně, že otec se sestry jdou konečně vypadnout a já se budu moct vyspat.
You're going to pretend you're not home?
Co se budeš dělat, že nejseš doma?
Of course.
No jasně.
I've already told all the boys in class I'm going to Grandma's in Vtelno.
Všem klukům ve třídě jsem už řekla, že jedu za babičkou do Vtelna.
But they'd come to your place, so why are you doing this?
Ale vždyť k tobě by šly, tak proč to děláš?
They'd come to your place too.
K tobě by taky šly.
Mom wouldn't let me open the door anyway.
Maminka by mi stejně nedovolila otevřít.
She says eggs don't grow on trees.
Říká, že vejce nerostou na stromech.
Sis!
Ségra!
Lexa, sorry.
Lexo, promiň.
I kind of got carried away.
Já jsem se do toho nějak zabrala.
How many do you think he'll whip out of people with this?
Kolik si myslíš, že toho s tímhle vymršká?
Tomas, you won't believe what they gave me at the competition.
Tomáši, neuvěříte, co mi v té sloze dali.
For what?
Za co?
I'm the best seller of CDs with animal sounds.
Jsem nejlepší prodejce CDček se zvuky zvířat.
Well I'll be, I never believed in animal sounds.
No vidíte, a já zvukům zvířat nevěřil.
I kept thinking, who on earth would buy fish voices.
Říkal jsem si, kdo by proboha koupil hlasy ryb.
Someone who's told by a skilled saleswoman that the fish voices were narrated by...
Ten, komu schopná prodejkyně řekne, že hlasy ryb namluvil.
Petr Narozny.
Petr Nárožný.
Good work.
Dobrá práce.
So show me the prize.
Tak ukažte tu cenu.
Wow, now that's an egg.
Panečku, tak to je vejce.
And I've got an Easter whip for Zoran.
A mám pomlázku pro Zorana.
I wouldn't mind one of those myself.
To bych si taky nechal líbit.
He'll be thrilled, he loves big things.
Bude nadšený, miluje velké věci.
And you're such a tiny little thing.
Přitom jsi taková malinká.
Easter really is great, isn't it?
Stejně jsou ty velikonoce príma, co?
I can't wait.
Už se nemůžu dočkat.
It's been so long since we celebrated Easter together with Zoran.
Už dlouho jsme je neslavili se Zoranem spolu.
Well then, should I whip you right now, today?
No tak to, abych vás vyšoupala rovnou dneska, ne?
No, but it wouldn't count.
No, ale to by neplatilo.
Feel free to stop by on Monday.
Klidně se stavte v pondělí.
And Zoran's southerner would still think it's for something else.
A Zoranův jižan ještě by si myslel, že je zatím něco jiného.
Zoran just loves carolers.
Zoranko, koledníky miluje.
He even orders his bodyguards to smile at them.
Dokonce přikazuje bodyguardům, aby se na ně usmívali.
Well, I'm not making any promises.
No, nic neslibuju.
You don't want me to wither away, do you?
Přece nechcete, abych uschla.
Marcelka.
Marcelko.
Can I hold it for a moment?
Můžu si ho vzít na chvilku do ruky?
Sure.
No.
Well, at least two kilos.
No, minimálně dvě kila.
Beautiful, see?
Krásné, vidíte?
They also offered me an elephant ear plant.
Ještě mi nabízeli sloní ucho.
And what would you do with it?
A na co by vám bylo?
It's great for polishing crystal, but I've already got one at home.
Skvěle se s ním leští křišťál, ale já už doma jedno mám.
And you won that one too?
A to jste taky vyhráli?
Last year.
Vloni.
For selling the double CD of large mammal wind sounds.
Za prodané dvojcédéčko větry velkých savců.
Oh right.
A jo.
Wait, what did you have to say to get someone to buy it?
Počkejte, a co jste musela říct, aby si ho někdo koupil?
Nothing.
Nic.
Ozzak bought it.
Koupil si ho Ozzák.
What is this?
Co to je?
Nothing for you.
Nic pro vás.
I want it.
To chci.
I'll braid you a new one.
Tak já ti upletu novou.
Yeah, and from what, when you've used up all the willow around here?
Jo a z čeho asi, když jsi všechno proutí vokolo už vypotřebovala?
Sis, can't we unravel it somehow? I won't meet my quota like this.
Ségra, nejde to nějak rozpárat, teď takhle limit nesplním.
Hey, Lexa.
Čau, Lexo.
Hi, Mom.
Ahoj, mami.
Hi.
Ahoj.
Mom, it's even more than last year again.
Mami, to je zase víc než loni.
Well, eggs don't grow on trees.
No, vejce nerostou na stromech.
But three hundred, that's just too much.
No, ale třista, to se nedá.
Sometimes I think even Sasa would do a better job.
Někdy si říkám, že by to i Saša zvládla líp.
But Mom, I'm a girl.
Ale mami, já jsem přece holka.
And that's a reason to give up on your family?
A kvůli tomu by ses vykašlala na rodinu?
When there's free food somewhere, we don't leave it lying there.
Když je někde jídlo zadarmo, tak ho tam nenecháme ležet.
Are the mushrooms growing yet?
Už se rostou houby?
Not yet, Mom.
Ještě ne, mami.
Then keep braiding.
Tak zatím pleť.
Ivuska?
Ivuško?
Yeah?
No?
Are you going to be much longer?
Máš to ještě nadlouho?
I just need to iron.
Já jen, že budu žehlit.
I'm vacuuming for the second time because of your mess.
Už to luxuju po druhý kvůli tomu vašemu bordelu.
Well I've got newspapers here.
No já mám tady noviny.
Damn, what a mess Ozzak made, give me that for the vacuum.
Sakra, co to ten Ozzák nadělal za svinčtvo, dej mi to do pleluxu.
Well then pick it up yourself first, won't you?
No tak si to hned dřív pozbírej, ne?
Damn, where does Ozzak get those branches?
Sakra, kde ten Ozzák ty pruty bere?
Hello.
Dobrý den.
Hi Iva.
Ahoj Ivo.
Hi Lexa.
Ahoj Lexo.
Wow, that's quite an Easter whip.
Tyjo, to je ale pomlázka.
What do you want?
Co chceš?
I came to ask if you're really not gonna be home tomorrow.
Já jsem se přišel zeptat, jestli fakt zejtra nebudeš doma.
She will be.
No bude.
Why wouldn't she be?
Proč by nebyla?
You're not going to Vtelno?
Ty nejdeš do Vtelna?
I am.
Jedu.
You're going to Vtelno?
Ty jedeš do Vtelna?
Why?
Proč?
You know, just normally.
No tak normálně.
I'm taking Grandma an Easter cake.
Vezu bábě mazanec.
To Vtelno?
Do Vtelna?
Nobody ever goes there for Easter.
Tam se přeci na velikonoce nikdy nejezdí.
No.
Ne.
Iva said she always goes.
Iva říkala, že jezdí vždycky.
Well, now she does.
No teď jo.
What kind of nonsense is going to Vtelno for Easter?
Co to je za nesmysl jezdit na Velikonoce do Vtelna?
God, why not?
Ježiš, a proč jako?
Grandma from Vtelno always goes to Libne for Easter every year.
Teď přece babička z Vtelna jezdí každý rok na Velikonoce do Libně.
Awesome!
Super!
Then I'll tell the boys at school too.
Tak to já řeknu i klukům ze školy.
Sure, tell them, so Ivuska doesn't wither away there.
No jasně, řekni, ať tam Ivuška neuschne.
No, no, no, don't say anything.
Ne, ne, ne, nic neříkej.
I'm not going anywhere.
Nepůjdu tady.
Jesus, Iva, please, don't be crazy.
Ježiš, Ivo, prosím tě, neblázni.
You're not going to take an Easter cake to an empty house.
Přece nepovezeš mazanec do prázdného baráku.
No, I won't.
No to nepovezu.
So Grandma isn't going to Libne this year?
Takže babička letos do Libně nejede?
No.
Ne.
Did you call her?
Ty jsi volala?
Yes.
Jo.
So she can hear again?
Takže ona už slyší?
Great, I'll call her right away.
No bezva, já to jí hned zavolám.
Why?
Proč?
Why isn't she going to Libne this year?
No proč letos nejede do té Libně?
You think she had another fight with Maruna?
Ale myslíš, že se zase pohádala s Marunou?
Jesus, don't call anyone.
Ježiš, nikam nevolej.
Why not?
A proč?
She won't talk to you anyway.
Stejně s tebou nebude mluvit.
She recently said she can hear.
Nedávno říkala, že slyší.
But she's not talking to anyone.
Ale ona nemluví s nikým.
But she'll talk to me.
Ale se mnou mluvit bude.
To no one.
S nikým.
But why, for God's sake?
A proč proboha?
Because nobody visits at Easter.
Protože na Velikonoce nikdo nejezdí.
But you go there.
No ale ty tam jezdíš.
Yeah.
No.
Well, do you get it?
No teda, chápeš to?
No.
Ne.
Goodbye then.
Tak nashle.
The botanical garden was once again visited by the Easter phantom, who last night pruned branches of the rare Babylon willow.
Botanickou zahradu opět navštívil velikonoční fantom a v noci na dnešek ořezal větve vzácné vrby babylonské.
But this year he made a mistake.
Letos ale udělal krok vedle.
The branches contained cocoons of the rare Cape painted moth.
Na větvích se nacházely kukly vzácného motýla pestřece kapského.
If they are not returned before they hatch, the garden will file criminal charges.
Pokud je nevrátí, než se vylíhnou, podá zahrada trestní oznámení.
Ivuska, how do you change the bags in the vacuum?
Ivuško, jak se vyndávají pytlíky z luxu?
Hey.
Čau.
So I found one.
Tak jsem jednu našla.
It's Russian, from Russia.
Je ruská, z Ruska.
Vodka?
Vodka?
Yeah, it's Russian vodka.
No, to je ruský vodka.
Premium.
Výborová.
That's the best kind.
Ta je nejlepší.
Are you making Ozzak's Russian eggs?
Děláš Ozzákovi ruský vejce?
Yeah, but I'll marinate them tonight.
Jo, ale naložím je až večer.
I won't make it in time at all.
Vůbec nestihnu.
But you're going to Vtelno on Monday, right?
Ale jedeš v pondělí do Vtelna, ne?
I hope so.
Doufám.
Just go, Vtelno is lovely.
Jen jeď, Vtelno je hezký.
The best.
Nejlepší.
What I like about you is how you keep it simple.
Co se mi líbí, jak to umíš jednoduše.
When I was young I'd always put on a mustache and pretend I was cousin Pepan from Moravia, just to avoid getting whipped.
Já za nána jsem si vždycky nasazovala knír a dělala jsem, že jsem bratranec Pepan z Moravy, abych se vyhnula praskla.
And nobody noticed?
A to ti nikdo nepoznal?
No, usually not.
Ne, většinou ne.
But Libor.
Ale Libor.
Libor always did.
Libor vždycky.
Whatever.
To je jedno.
I wouldn't let anyone whip me at Easter, not even my husband.
Já bych se na Velikonoce nenechala mlátit ani od manžela.
Well, who's talking about Easter?
No, kdo mluví o Velikonocích?
Anyway.
No nic.
Just go.
Jen jeď.
Even though Lexa will miss getting an egg from you.
I když to vajíčko od tebe bude Lexovi chybět.
I made him one anyway.
Já jsem mu ho stejně udělala.
Even though I didn't want to.
I když jsem nechtěla.
Thanks.
Dík.
And that vodka was swiped by Horvat.
A tu vodku spajcoval Horvát.
Since we're being honest.
Když už jsme v těch upřímnostech.
I know.
Já vím.
But Ozzak won't notice anyway.
Ale Ozzák to stejně nepozná.
Exactly.
Přesně.
Bye then.
Tak čau.
Bye.
Čau.
Sasa cooked?
Saša vařila?
Yeah.
Jo.
Lexa?
Lexo?
Only 329 to go.
Už jenom 329.
Mom, you raised my quota again?
Mami, ty jsi mi zase zvýšila limit?
So what?
No a?
You can't raise my quota without telling me!
Nemůžeš mi zvýšit limit a nic mi o tom neříct?
And you can grow up without telling me?
A ty můžeš vyrůst a nic mi o tom neříct?
Why do you always make trouble?
Proč pořád děláš problémy?
But I have problems!
Ale já mám problémy!
I have to get up at six, instead of an Easter whip my sister braided me this thing again.
Musím vstávat v šest, místo pomlázky mi ségra zase upletla tohle.
And almost all the girls in class are going to their grandma's for Easter.
A skoro všechny holky ze třídy jedou na Velikonoce k babičce.
Krutova isn't going.
Krutová nejede.
Titanic?
Titanic?
I already arranged it with her mom, she's really looking forward to it.
Už jsem ti to domluvila s její mámou, moc se těší.
Mom, last time she locked me in her room.
Mami, minule jsi se mnou zamkla v pokoji.
But she gave ten eggs.
Ale dala deset vajec.
Lexa, I don't know what's wrong with you.
Lexo, já nevím, co to s tebou je.
Who raised such a selfish kid?
Kdo z tebe vychoval takovýho sobce?
Sorry.
Promiň.
Sasa doesn't complain and brings mushrooms too.
Saša neremcá a houby nosí.
Just one?
Jenom jeden?
Sorry.
Promiň.
Ozzak's gonna flip.
Ozzák bude koukat.
What?
Co?
I know where he gets those long branches.
Už vím, kde bere to dlouhý proutí.
The botanical garden.
Botanická.
How much did he pay?
Kolik zaplatil?
Nothing.
Nic.
I returned the cocoons and they were so thrilled they let me cut some branches too.
Vrátil jsem jim ty kukly a oni byli tak nadšeni, že mi dovolili nařezat si taky.
Great.
No bezva.
So you'll be making a mess here again?
Takže tady zase budeš dělat svinčík?
On the way I ran into Sasa and she offered to braid me an Easter whip.
Cestou jsem potkal Sašu a ta se mi nabídla, že mi pomlázku uplete.
Ozzak's going to be surprised.
Ozzák se bude divit.
Yeah, watch out you're not the one surprised.
No, aby ses nedivil ty.
What?
Co?
Nothing.
Nic.
Want a schnitzel?
Dáš si řízek?
Schnitzel?
Řízek?
Yeah, I've got pork and chicken.
No, mám vepřový i kuřecí.
Schnitzel for dinner?
Že řízek k večeři?
So what?
No a?
Nothing.
Nic.
Any stuffing?
Nádivka by nebyla?
No.
Ne.
Shame.
Škoda.
I just mean, on Sundays we usually have it.
No já jen, že vždycky v neděli bývá.
So you won't have any.
Takže si nedáš.
Well, since you already made it...
No tak když už to udělala...
Who are you calling this late?
Kam voláš, tak pozdě.
Vtelno.
Do Vtelna.
Jesus.
Ježiš.
That mom is awful.
Ta máma je hrozná.
She's been calling me since seven and still not picking up.
Volá mi už od sedmi a furt to nebere.
Maybe she just can't hear it.
Třeba to jenom neslyší.
But I bought her one of those blinking things for the phone.
Ale vždycky jsem jí koupil takový to blikátko k telefonu.
So she doesn't see it.
No tak ho nevidí.
But her eyesight is fine, she reads all the time.
Ale vidí dobře, furt čte.
I hope she's okay.
Doufám, že je v pořádku.
I'm sure.
Určitě.
You're going there tomorrow anyway, so you'll check on her.
No ty tam stejně zítra jedeš, takže ji zkontrolujéš.
Sure.
Jasně.
What if she's lying somewhere on the floor injured and can't get to the phone?
Jestli tam někde neleží zraněná na zemi a nemůže k telefonu.
Dad, relax.
Tati, klid.
Grandma is fine.
Babička je v pořádku.
You think?
Myslíš?
I'm sure.
Jsem si jistá.
She's in Libne, she has nothing to worry about.
Je v Libni, nemusí se vůbec ničeho bát.
In Libne?
V Libni?
You think she made up with Maruna?
Ale myslíš, že už se s Marunou udobřily?
Definitely.
Určitě.
Go to bed.
Běž spát.
You and Ozzak have a lot to do tomorrow.
Zítra toho máte s Ozzákem moc.
That'll be Sasa.
To bude Saša.
She's bringing my Easter whip.
Nese mi tu pomlázku.
Sasa?
Sašo?
I kind of got carried away.
Já jsem se do toho nějak zabrala.
Oh, that one's me.
Ó, ten jsem já.
But I've got an Easter whip.
Ale já mám pomlázku.
Excuse me.
No dovol.
Move.
Uhni.
But don't show off too much.
Ale moc se nevytahuj.
It'll end up the same as always anyway.
Stejně to dopadne, jako vždycky.
Bet you.
Vsaď se.
Krrr.
Krrí.
Wait, Ozzak, Easter without Easter cake.
Počkej, Ozzáku, velikonoce bez mazance.
Shut up about the cake, let's get whipping!
Sklapni, mazance, teď se šupe!
Ivuska, Dad and I are going to give you a little whipping now, but we mean well, you know that, right?
Ivuško, my tě tady teď s tátou trošku zmlátíme, ale myslíme to v dobrým, to doufám, víš?
Yeah, sure.
Jo, jasně.
And even though I'm the only one here with an Easter whip worth mentioning, after all, bro, he's the father.
No, a i když jsem jedinej, kdo tady má pomlázku, která stojí za řeč, nás nebrácha, je to otec.
Ivuska, happy Easter and stay healthy.
Ivuško, hezký velikonoce a ať jsi zdravá.
Easter, Easter, to the water, I'm a little bunny.
Hody, hody do provody, já jsem malý zajíček.
I ran along the water, carried a bunch of little eggs, met a little partridge...
Utíkal jsem podél vody, nesl kopu vajíček, potkal mě koroptviček...
Forget the partridge, okay?
Kašli na koropte, ne?
Now me...
Teď já...
Of course, I'll start.
Samozřejmě, tak já začnu.
Fine.
Dobře.
So you don't wither away.
Abys nám neuschla.
Easter, Easter to the...
Hody, hody do...
Easter to the...
Hody do...
Damn it, nothing again.
Dočerta, zase nic.
I just can't bring myself to whip you.
Já tě prostě prásknout nedokážu.
It doesn't matter, it's fine anyway.
To nevadí, stejně dobrý.
What good is a big Easter whip, you wimp?
Na co ti je velká pomlázka, srabe?
Wait at the building manager's.
Počkej u správcový.
Hold on!
No moment!
No building manager!
Žádná správcová!
What is it?
Co je?
Is Ozzak here?
Je tu Ozzák?
I don't know.
Nevím.
I lost him on the mezzanine.
Ztratil jsem ho v mezipatře.
Relax, he'll find his way.
A klid, teď trefí.
He definitely went to the building manager's on his own.
On určitě šel sám na správcovou.
Uncle?
Strýdo?
Is the coast clear?
Už je čistý vzduch.
What do you mean clear?
Jak čistý vzduch?
Is my brother here?
No jestli je tady brácha.
No.
Není.
Great, I'm taking the car keys.
Super, beru si klíče od auta.
Fine.
Jo.
Uncle!
Strýdo!
Relax, I didn't even have a single Russian egg.
Klid, neměl jsem ani jedno ruský vejce.
What now?
Co je zase?
Iva, we've got a problem.
Ivo, průšvih.
What?
Co?
He's not at the building manager's.
U správcový není.
So?
No a?
So I don't know where he is.
Takže nevím, kde je.
Neither do I, but he took the car keys.
Já taky ne, no, ale bral si klíče od auta.
Great, you're not in Vtelno.
Super, ty nejsi ve Vtelně.
If you must know.
Pokud ti vypadne.
No, wait, Iva, I need to whip you.
Ne, počkej, Ivo, já tě musím vyšoupat.
Forget it.
Na to zapomeň.
Iva.
Ivo.
No.
Ne.
Then just give me the eggs, or I'll have to make a mark.
Tak mi dej jenom vajíčka, nebo budu muset zakroužkovat.
Sorry, someone's knocking.
Promiň, klope.
The car is gone.
Auto zmizelo.
What do we do?
Co budeme dělat?
I don't know about you, but I'm going to lie down in my room.
Já nevím, jak vy, ale já si dolehnu do pokoje.
Wait, you're not going to Vtelno?
Počkej, ty nejdeš do Vtelna?
Sorry, someone's knocking.
Promiň, klope.
It's already eleven.
Už je jedenáct.
I've been everywhere.
Jsem úplně všude.
At Krutova's too, I hope.
U Krutový taky doufám.
Yeah.
No.
She wanted a kiss for each egg.
Chtěla za každý pusu.
And how many did you collect?
A kolik jsi vykoledoval?
Five.
Pět.
Didn't she have more eggs?
Víc vajec neměla?
A whole tray, but then she started sticking her tongue in my mouth.
Plný plato, ale pak mi začala strkat jazyk do pusy.
And when I said I'd rather swallow a slug, she started crying and ate twelve of them.
A když jsem řekl, že bych radši polknul slimáka, tak začala brečet a dvanáct mi jich sežrala.
Well, Lexa.
No, Lexo.
Sasa is going to have to try harder.
Saša se bude muset snažit.
The mushrooms will still grow.
Teď houby ještě narostou.
Exactly.
No, právě.
What?
Co?
Where is Ozzak?
Kde je Ozzák?
I don't know.
Já nevím.
He's definitely at your place.
Určitě je u vás.
I followed him.
Sledovala jsem ho.
Come out and give back the eggs!
Vylezte a vraťte vejce!
Please, don't yell, my head is splitting.
Prosím vás, nekřičte, nebo vypraskne hlava.
Your uncle stole my husband's eggs.
Tvůj strýc okradl mého muže o jeho vejce.
I had to use pepper spray.
Musela jsem použít pepřový sprej.
Ozzak!
Ozzáku!
What?
Cože?
He came for the Easter whipping and I was dumb enough to let him in.
Přijel na pomlázku a já husa jsem ho pustila dovnitř.
I'll come get you!
Já si pro vás dojdu!
What is it?
Co je?
Is that you, Mambo?
To jste vy, Mambo?
Don't play games with me, where's that egg?
Nehrajte na mě divadýlko, kde je to vejce?
Don't yell at me.
Neřvěte na mě.
You scoundrel!
Lotře!
I was asleep, look, my eyes are still puffy.
Já spal, podívejte se, jak mám ještě opuchlý oči.
Hold on!
No moment!
There'll be consequences.
To bude mít dohru.
And Ivuska, you should clean up his room a bit.
A Ivuško, měla bys mu tam trošku uklidit.
It's full of moths.
Je to tam samej motýl.
My whole Easter is ruined.
Já mám zkažený celý Velikonoce.
Uncle, don't cry.
Strýdo, tak nebreč.
You're a man, after all.
Vždyť jsi chlap.
It's the pepper spray.
To ten pepřák.
Iva, we've got a problem.
Ivo, průšvih.
Obviously, it's Easter.
Pochopitelně, vždyť jsou velikonoce.
Mom's not in Libne.
Máma v Libni není.
What?
Cože?
Maruna wished me happy Easter, so I asked for Mom on the phone.
Maruna mi přála k velikonocům, tak jsem chtěl mámu k telefonu.
She said she's not there.
Říkala, že tam není.
God, I hope nothing happened to Mom.
Ježiš, aby se tak mámě něco stalo.
So I guess we'll drive to Vtelno.
Tak to asi pojedeme do Vtelna.
And you're not driving, bro, I had the Russian eggs.
A nebude řídit ty brácha, já měl ruský vejce.
Is anyone here?
Je tady někdo?
That's what you look like.
Takhle vypadáš.
Lexa.
Lexo.
Actually, you look pretty good.
Náhodou vypadáš docela dobře.
Kind of like Mom's cousin who used to visit us at Easter.
Trochu jako ten mámin bratranec, co k nám jezdíval na velikonoce.
That's a cactus branch, Mom won't count that.
To je píchavka, to ti máma neuzná.
I don't care.
To je mi jedno.
Lexa?
Lexo?
Yeah?
No?
You know nobody's whipped me yet this year?
Víš, že mě letos ještě nikdo nevyšoupal?
Sis, cut it out.
Ségra, neser.
Come on.
Pojď.
But don't hit too hard.
Ale nemlať moc.
Don't worry.
Neboj.
Ow.
Au.
That doesn't hurt.
To nebolí.
I'd like to see you try.
Já chtěla bych vidět tebe.
Go ahead.
Klidně.
Doesn't hurt.
Nebolí.
Ow, give it back.
Au, smětovrať.
Ow.
Au.
It's already past noon anyway.
Stejně už bylo poledne.
Going home?
Jedeme domů?
I can tell you now.
Už ti to můžu soudit.
Once we get past Vtelno, Mom can see just fine.
Až vyjedeme za Vtelno, máma vidí dobře.
Take a bite, that'll settle it somehow.
Koušle to, tak to nějak vydáš.
I just don't understand her.
A já to s tebou nechápu.
I was so worried about her.
Já měl o ní takovej strach.
I wasn't.
Já ne.
And she's been sitting locked up at home every Easter for years, not answering the phone.
A ona si už tolik let celý Velikonoce sedí zamčená doma a nebere telefony.
Eating chocolate, knitting, watching TV, and telling the whole family she's in Libne.
Jí čokoládu, plete, kouká na televizi a rozhlásí po celým příbuzenstvu, že je v Libni.
I don't get it.
Nechápu.
Have some of the third-pint.
Dej si ten trojku.
Thanks.
Dík.
I'm not surprised at all, honestly, that they keep fighting.
Já se vůbec nedivím, ty varovně, že se pohádají.
Maybe she just got tired of all the cleaning, boiling, and baking Easter cakes, you know.
Třeba jí prostě jenom přestalo bavit, furt gruntovat, vyvářet a péct mazance, no.
Surely that can be resolved like normal people, right?
Tak snad se to dá řešit jako normálně mezi lidmi, ne?
Sure.
Jasně.
But those Easter cakes, bro, those were really something, weren't they?
Ale ty mazance, brácha, ty bejvávaly, co?
You get it?
Pochopuješ?
But I prefer Ivuska's.
Ale mám radši od Ivušky.
Oh right, Ivuska's are great too.
A jo, Ivuška taky.
You could've asked for the recipe too.
Taky sis mohl navzít recept.